softness can overcome hardness, but hardness can overcome softness
juuyokugou wo seishimashite gouyokujuu motatsu
if you're too focused on showing off, my alarm will go off
muchuu de kakkou tsukete mo hijou beru ga naru
walk fifty steps forward in a reckless style
gojuuppo ijou mo saki aruite chottotsumoushinna sutairu
you're moody and do as you please; no matter what I do, you ignore me
jiyuu de kibunya no kimi wa douyattatte mushi
there's a mystery that no one can solve, I shiver when the wind blows
darenimo tokenai nazo ga aru fukidashita kaze ni furueteru
I'll unravel this maze
kono meiro wo hodoite yaru
you laughed, will it rain tomorrow?
kimi ga waratta ashita wa ame kai
the wise light flickers
soumeina hikari ga chikachika hikaru
you've got to focus your eyes before the future changes
me wo korasanakucha mirai ga kawatte shimau mae ni
I'm sure, I'm sure this moment will be swept away
kitto kitto ima wo saratte iku
I have to be with you, otherwise the future might dry up
kimi to janakucha mirai wa kawaite shimau no kamo
hurry up, because I'm sure that we'll smile back on this moment
isoge kitto ima wo waratte iku
The Soul Living Inside the Puppet
どりゃ～！
うお～！
（ミフネ）ひけ！　ひけ～！
Retreat... Retreat!
（カンクロウ）
一流の傀儡使いのチャクラ糸は→
The Chakra Threads of world-class
Puppet Masters can control humans
傀儡だけじゃなく
人も操ることができる。
as well as their puppets.
だが　チャクラ糸を切ってしまえば
操られてるヤツに害はないじゃん。
But once the Chakra Thread is cut,
there's no harm to the human.
かたじけない。
味方を殺めるところであった。
I'm indebted to you.
I was about to slay an ally.
傀儡使いには
傀儡使いの戦い方があるからな。
There's a special way to fight
between Puppet Users.
まっ
俺が引き受けるしかないじゃん。
And I'm the only one here
who can do this...
なあ　チヨバア！
Right, Granny Chiyo?!
（チヨバア）カンクロウ。
Kankuro...
ん？
《サソリ…。
Sasori...
わしのしてきたことは
間違いばかりじゃった。
I erred in everything I did...
じゃが　ナルトに出会い
最後に正しいことができた。
But after meeting Naruto,
I was able to do
the right thing in the end.
そして未来に希望を残し
死ねたはずじゃった。
I thought I died,
leaving some hope
for a bright future.
じゃがな　やはりお前を前にすれば
後悔の過去を思い出してしまう。
But...
As I stand before you,
I can't help
but regret the past... Sasori...
サソリよ…》
((サソリ：お父様と　お母様は
いつ戻られますか？
When are mother and father
coming back?
うん　もう少し
先になるらしいのう。
Well, they'll be gone a little bit longer...
(そうですか…))
I see...
《チヨバア：わしには　本当のことを
伝えることができなかった。
I couldn't bring myself
to tell him the truth...
両親の死を知らせるには
サソリは　あまりにも幼すぎた》
Sasori was too young to know
about his parents' deaths...
((うん？
(サソリ…))
Sasori...
《チヨバア：気づいておったのじゃ。
サソリは両親の死を…》
Sasori had already figured out,
that his parents were dead.
((コムシ：サソリ！　元気してるか？
Sasori! How've you been?
Huh?
この前の傀儡も
評判がよかったって→
Granny Chiyo said
your last puppet was a huge hit.
チヨバア様が言ってたぜ。
俺も　いつか　オメエの傀儡ぐらい
すげぇ！　って言われる忍に…。
Some day, I want to be
a shinobi like you,
where everyone praises my puppets...
（コムシ）おい！　聞いてんのかよ？
Hey! Are you listening?!
お～い　俺ですよ～。
Hey, it's me!
コムシが来ましたよ～。
Komushi has come
to see you!
おい！　返事しろって！
Hey! Answer me!
あ…。
わ…　わざとじゃないぞ。
悪かったよ。
H-Hey, I didn't mean it.
I'm sorry.
でも　俺の扱い
もしかして人形以下か？
But you're treating me worse
than a puppet.
まあ　お前のリアクションに→
Oh well, I might as well wait
until hell freezes over
いちいち落ち込んでたら
キリがないからな。
to get a response from you.
チヨバア様からの言づてだ。
I have a message from Granny Chiyo.
依頼しておいた
傀儡の納期を早め…。
She wants the puppets
she ordered sooner...
（サソリ）烏　黒蟻　山椒魚。
The Crow, Black Ant and Salamander...
Oh...
依頼書どおり　造形完了。
Everything she requested is done.
へ～っ　これが新作か。
しかし　ずいぶんと早く…。
Oh, so these are your new creations.
待たせるのは嫌いだ。
Man, that was quick...
I don't like to keep people waiting.
そうか…　そうだよな。
Yeah... That's true.
（コムシ）へ～っ…。
Hey... That's amazing.
大したもんだな。
まるで人の指みたいだ。
They look so human!
（サソリ）ふむ…。
あっ…　おっと　忘れるとこだった。
Oh, I almost forgot.
その新作の…
烏用の毒を　どうするか→
About your new creation...
She asked me to inquire about
the poison for the Crow puppet.
それも聞いとけって
言われたんだ。
うん？
Huh?
希少薬草ばっかじゃん　これ。
These are all rare medicinal plants!
これを調合するってのか？
You're gonna make
a mixture out of these?
けど　こりゃ　許可証が必要だな。
This is going to require permission.
よし！　このコムシ様が
掛け合ってやるからさ→
All right!
I, Komushi, will negotiate this!
So give me some time.
ちょっと待っててくれ…。
待つのは　イヤだ。
I don't want to wait.
だよな。　じゃ　行こうぜ。
I guess not. Then let's go!
（コムシ）コムシです。
なんじゃ？
It's me, Komushi!
What is it?
おお　伝言　伝えて…。
Oh... Did you relay my message...?
チヨバア様
サソリから　お願いがあるんだ。
Granny Chiyo, Sasori has a request.
なんじゃ？
What is it?
フム…　配合比率がわからんと
なんとも言えないが…。
There's not much I can say
without knowing the blending ratio
of the mixture.
おぬしのことじゃ。　問題なかろう。
But since this is coming from you,
I have no issues with it.
医薬部には　話をつけておく。
I'll clear it with
the Pharmaceuticals Division.
わしは研究の続きがあるゆえ
もう下がれ。
I'm in the middle of research,
so you may leave.
（コムシ）あ～あ　サソリは　いいよな。
Man, you've got it made, Sasori.
その歳で立派に
里の役に立ってるんだもんな。
You're still young, but you're already
contributing to the village.
チヨバア様も鼻が高いだろ。
Granny Chiyo must be
so proud of you.
聞いてるのか？
Are you listening to me?
チヨバア様は　いつも
お前のこと気にかけてるんだぜ。
Granny Chiyo is always
worried about you.
俺もさ　早くお前の傀儡みたいに→
I can't wait to be acknowledged
as a full-fledged shinobi...
一人前の忍として認められたいぜ。
just like your puppets!
うちの親は　いつも
俺を　ガキ扱いなんだよ。
My own parents still treat me
like a kid!
忍に向いてないって。
They tell me I'm not suited
to being a shinobi...
でも　今度
国境の警備を任されたんだ。
But this time,
I was assigned to border security.
そりゃ　ただの警備だけど
そこで手柄を立てれば…。
It's just guard duty,
but if I can prove myself...
コムシ！
こんな時間まで何してるの？
Komushi!
What have you been doing
at this hour?!
心配するでしょ。
I was so worried!
ちょっ…
やめてくれよ　かっこわるい。
Wait... Cut it out,
you're embarrassing me!
これから
俺だって警備の任務に…。
I'm going to be assigned border
security missions from now on...
任務なんて断ったっていいのよ！
You can turn down things
like missions!
母さんが
一生　面倒みてあげるから。
I'll take care of you
for the rest of my life.
（コムシ）だから　やめろって！
I want you to stop it!
サンキュー！　サソリ。
Thanks, Sasori!
聞いたぞ。　任務で
ケガをしたというではないか。
I heard that you were injured on duty?
ヘマをしちまって。　でもね…。
I messed up.
But...
なんと！　傀儡の腕を…。
That's... a puppet arm!
それだけじゃないんですよ！
That's not all!
ヘヘヘ！
前より強くなった気分です。
I feel stronger than before.
それに　本当　ピッタリなんだよな。
And it fits perfectly.
もともと
俺の体だったみたいなんすよ。
It feels like it's always been
a part of my body.
（コムシ）ぐわ～っ！
仕込みの毒を　自ら食らうとは…。
How could you ingest
your own poison?!
（コムシ）チヨバア様
アイツは…　アイツは悪くねえ。
Granny Chiyo...
He's... He's not to blame.
悪いのは　ドジを踏んだ俺…。
I'm the one... who messed up...
ぐわ～っ！
え～い！　サソリは！？
毒の配合比率は　まだか？
Where is Sasori?!
Do we have the blending ratio
of the poison yet?
うわ～っ！
治してください　治してください
治してください　治して！
Please heal him...
Heal him! Please!
右腕だって
あなたが　つけたんでしょ！？
You attached his right arm too, right?
なら　左腕も…。
Then his left arm can be...
足も　体も…
魂だって　治せるはずでしょ！
His legs, his body...
You can even heal his soul, can't you?!
(返して！　私のコムシを
治して　返してください！！))
Give him back to me!
Heal my Komushi and
give him back to me!
《痛ましい事故であった。
It was a painful accident.
コムシは　わしとサソリを
よく　つないでくれた。
Komushi was my link to Sasori...
それだけではない。
Not only that...
サソリにとっても　唯一といっていい
友じゃったのに…》
He was Sasori's only friend.
((サソリの近況は　どうじゃ？
How has Sasori been lately?
ふだんと変わりありませんよ。
The same as usual.
最近は
細かい傀儡のパーツを作ってますね。
He's been working on
small puppet parts recently.
(これが　本当に人の手みたいで…))
And they look like
real human hands...
((ん！？　なんじゃ？　まさか…。
偶然のはずじゃが…。
Huh? What?
Impossible. It has to be a coincidence...
何かが…。
But something is...
《思い過ごしで
あってくれればよいが…》
I hope my fears are ungrounded!
（サソリ）待たせるのは嫌いだ。
I don't like to make people wait.
目測では　もう少し
成長するかと思ったが…。
From what I can see,
I thought there'd be
a little more progress.
サソリ！　何をしておる！？
Sasori! What are you doing?!
ぎりぎり　規格のサイズに収まったか。
You barely got it to
the standard size...
サソリ…。
Sasori!
コムシじゃと！？
It's Komushi?!
(（サソリ）依頼どおり　造形完了))
As requested...
The model is finished.
《わしは　あやつが最もつらいとき
そばにいてやれなんだ。
I wasn't able to be at his side
when he was suffering the most.
愛情を最も欲したときにそばに…。
When he desperately needed love...
いや　本当は　あやつのもとから
口実をつくって逃げていた。
No, I made excuses and
distanced myself from him.
わしが　あやつを
あのように歪めてしまった。
I'm the one who distorted him.
すまぬ。　よみがえった死人が→
I'm sorry...
Much good it does at this point...
傀儡になったお前に
謝ったところで今更じゃが…》
An apology from a reanimated corpse
to the puppet that you are now!
技のキレは　さすがじゃん。
Your technique is as sharp as ever.
だが　闘志が宿ってねえ。
But you don't have any fighting spirit!
やっぱ　傀儡使いが操られてちゃ
ダメってことじゃん。
I guess Puppet Masters aren't good
at being a puppet, eh?
フン　若造が　わかったようなことを。
Inexperienced ones shouldn't act
as if they know....
この穢土転生という術を
あなどるでないぞ。
Don't make light of
the Reanimation Jutsu.
術者が本気になれば…。
If the user of the jutsu gets serious...
Oh, speak of the devil!
言うとるそばから…。
裏白秘技　十機偽松の集！
Reverse Secret White Technique...
Esematsu's Ten Puppets!
えっ　ワイヤーじゃと？
What?!
Wires?
な…。
Wha—?!
サソリも　このサソリの父と母も→
Sasori... as well as
Sasori's Mother and Father...
俺が回収して直したんだ。
I recovered and repaired them.
((サクラ：アイツは　サソリは言ってました。
Sasori told me...
自分は人形に
なりきれなかった人間だって。
that he was a human
who wasn't able to become a puppet.
生身の核を持つ
不完全な傀儡だって。
An incomplete puppet with
a core that was living flesh...
傀儡になった
お父さんと　お母さんに→
Do you think he wanted to
be closer to his parents
近づきたかったんですかね。
who had become puppets?
魂のない人形に
なりたいだなんて。
How could anyone want to
become a puppet without a soul?
そうかもな。　だけどよ→
Possibly...
But you know...
俺には　この傀儡
サソリの父と母に宿る魂を感じるぜ。
I can sense the souls of
Sasori's mother and father
inside these puppets.
サソリのヤツも
それを感じたと信じたい。
I'd like to believe that
Sasori felt it as well.
チヨバア様が言ってました。
Granny Chiyo said...
お父さんとお母さんの
最後の攻撃は→
that Sasori was able to see
his mother and father's final attack.
サソリに見えていた。　それでも
なぜかかわさなかったって。
But for some reason,
he didn't counter it.
(ああ　伝わったんだろうな。
父と母の魂の叫びってヤツがよ))
Yeah... It must've reached him.
The cry of his parents' souls.
確かに　俺は若造じゃん。
I admit I'm inexperienced.
だが
チャクラ糸を通して伝わってくる→
But I'm not so ignorant
that I couldn't feel
アンタの後悔や悲しみに
気づかないほど鈍感じゃないぜ。
your regret and sadness
through your Chakra Threads.
You say the first thing
that pops up in your mind!
ぬけぬけと思ったことを
言いおって。
だから　若造というんじゃ。
That's why you're inexperienced!
償いたくても償えないこともある。
There are things one wants
to atone for, but can't.
ましてや　わしは死人じゃ。
Besides, I'm a corpse.
どうすることもできんわい。
There's nothing I can do!
俺は　サソリに託されたんだ。
Sasori entrusted me...
((サソリ：父と母の傀儡も
お前に託す))
I entrust you with the Father
and Mother puppets.
サソリが　おぬしに…。
Sasori entrusted you...?!
（カンクロウ）さすが
サソリが作った傀儡だ。
Puppets that only Sasori could create.
仕込みはもちろん
指先に至るまで→
Their workings are so delicate...
all the way down to the fingertips.
繊細に作りこまれている。
《こやつもサソリ同様→
So he shares a love and
passion for puppets,
傀儡への並々ならぬ愛情を
持っておるのか》
just like Sasori did?
この２人には　サソリの魂が宿ってる。
Sasori's soul dwells in
these two puppets!
そして　その思いが→
And his love instilled the souls
of his parents in them too!
傀儡に父と母の魂をも宿らせた。
少なくともサソリは
そう感じていたはずだ。
Sasori, at least, was able to feel it.
傀儡に魂じゃと？
Puppets with souls?!
それだけじゃないぜ　チヨバア。
That's not all, Granny Chiyo...
父と母を操演したアンタの思いも→
The love you gave to
his Father and Mother puppets
魂となって
この２人に宿ってるんだ。
became a part of their souls.
Huh?
サソリは　それをわかっていた。
Sasori was aware of that.
すべてをひっくるめて
サソリは俺に…。
And he gave them all to me...
いや　未来の忍世界に託したのさ。
Rather, he entrusted them to me
for future generations
of the shinobi world.
それを受け継いで
伝えていくのも→
Passing it on is our duty too.
俺たちの役目ってわけじゃん。
サソリが…。
Sasori did that...?
たしかに　俺は　若造で→
Sure, I'm inexperienced and
in your eyes, a stranger.
アンタから見れば
他人かもしれねえ。
だが弟は　我愛羅は→
But my kid brother...
Gaara received your soul
and came back to life.
アンタの魂を貰って
生き返ったんだ。
とても他人とは　思えねえ。
So I'm not a stranger at all.
それに
チャクラ糸を通して感じるんだ。
And I can sense it through
the Chakra Threads.
サソリと父と母　家族の思いが→
Sasori and his mother and father...
The family's thoughts, their love...
魂の声がこう言っている。
Their souls are saying...
チヨバアを止めてやってくれってな。
"Please stop Granny Chiyo!"
家族…。
Family...
((母さん！　たかが
家族の記念写真なんだから→
Mother!
It's only a family portrait.
Don't be so stubborn.
そんなに強情にならなくても。
バカもん。
忍んでこその忍じゃ。
You fool! The meaning of
the word "shinobi" is to be stealthy!
そんなものを撮って
写真立てに飾り→
I will not take a photo,
to be put up as decoration...
ホームパーチーなんぞで
「よいお写真ですね」なんて→
and have people say,
"Oh, what a fine photo" at parties!
言われるのは
まっぴらごめんじゃ。
そ　そこまでは　言ってませんけど。
W-We wouldn't go that far...
言ってるも同然じゃわい。
Of course, you will!
（サソリ）チヨバア様。
Granny Chiyo...
写真　一緒に撮るの嫌なの？
Don't you want to take
a photo with us?
No... It's not that.
いや　そういうことを
言っておるのでは…。
もう　しようがないな。
What are we going to do with you?
おおう…　何をする！
Oh, what are you doing?
む～。
(ああ！！))
– Oh!
– Hey!
それにしても　よき操演者に
引き継がれたものよ。
I will say though,
they are in the hands
of a fine puppeteer.
あっ！
チヨバア！！
Granny Chiyo!
な～んてな。　リアル死んだふり。
Just kidding!
Playing Possum for real!
ゲヘ　ゲヘ　ゲヘヘヘヘヘ。
さて　サソリが父と母を→
Now then...
Sasori left his Mother and Father
to you as a present...
置き土産として
置いていったのに→
わしが何も残さんわけには
いかんのう。
I must leave you with something too.
今のわしが
お前に残してやれるのは→
All I can give you now are
my Secret Puppetry Techniques.
傀儡の奥義くらいのもんじゃ。
その身をもって学ぶがよい。
Learn, by experiencing them firsthand!
（カンクロウ）ちょっと待っ…。
（チヨバア）白秘技奥義　夢幻の集！
Hey, wait...!
Secret White Technique!
Army of Illusions!
マジやべえじゃん！
This is bad!
（チヨバア）アッハッハ！
（カンクロウ）ガキの頃　あんなに
修業つけてくれって→
When I was a kid,
I begged you to train me.
せがんだのに　里の未来なんか
どうでもいいって→
But you said you didn't care
about the future of the village
相手にしてくれなかったじゃん！
and totally ignored me!
（チヨバア）わしも若かったからのう。
I guess I was young back then too!
（カンクロウ）十分　ババアだったじゃん！
You were already
an old hag by then!
（チヨバア）アーハッハッハ！
I was tired of walking and didn't know what I should do
aruki tsukarete tohou ni kureta
my teacher told me to go towards a bright future
akarui mirai e sensei wa iu kedo
but which way should I go to find the light?
docchi ni aruitara hikari wa sasu kana
I have no idea at the moment so let's go
toriaezu wakaranai kedo ikouze
don't tell me things I want to hear
kirei goto nanka maji kan kanben desu
just give me something so powerful that it hurts
itai kurai tsuyoi yatsu wo choudai
I'm rebelling against the ordinary life
arikitari na mainichi ni hankou desu
burning up the mic with our rock
tagire m i c oretachi no rock
I can hear you are screaming
kimino koe ga kikoeru
that's the only thing that's real, let it explode
sore dake wa real sa hajikero
this song
kono uta
i can hear you are screaming
I'm running through the night on impulse
tsuki ugokasare shoudou no mama ni yoru wo kakenda
can't you see can't you see can't you see my face
I want to sense this moment not just the words, I want to sense you
kotoba ja nai ima dake wo kanjitetai kimi wo kanjitetai
i can hear you are screaming
keep on shouting and open the door to tomorrow
sakebi tsuzukete ashita no tobira wo kojihirakerunda
don't worry don't worry don't worry baby
I want to believe in us, not anyone else, I want to believe in my dream
dareka ja nai oretachi wo shinjitetai yume wo shinjitetai
Did you say Omoi deserted
the battlefield?!
Is this true, Kakashi?
Yes. Reports say he ran
from his post
after saying he needed
to leave for a bit.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Deserting one's post under
enemy fire
is considered a serious offense
in the Hidden Cloud Village!
美空ひばりです。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Run, Omoi!"
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Damn it, Omoi,
what are you thinking?!
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート。
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』
２時間スペシャル。